foreign
[Music]
this day putting some leftovers out for
the Hungry Birds and making some snow
cream it is a delicious treat I can only
make this time of year
winter has found me staying at home more
than usual cozied up in blankets after a
long day working and living within four
walls
[Music]
foreign
I grew up watching movies and reading
books that portrayed Misfit Heroes who
stumbled upon a quest having to face
their greatest fears in order to succeed
in their life
more often than not their success
involved finding friends along the way
that supported them on their Journey
the hero was no longer a lone Wanderer
instead he was part of a group it was
what he had needed all along over the
course of their story these characters
often find friends who teach them the
meaning of life
these are wonderful and sacred stories
about love and connection many of which
I cherish today
but I admit even as a child I was
attracted to the side characters that
were more sage-like and quiet monks and
sacred Wise Women people that were on
unconventional paths and yet contributed
to the story in crucial ways
[Music]
foreign
has never been as easy for me as these
protagonists particularly in the region
of finding a group of friends I was an
extremely socially awkward child I was
practically mute half the time the more
time I spent in a school and around
people I found I needed time away in the
forest beside my home daydreaming alone
and finding energy to face The Busy
World again
or perhaps I only needed one or two very
close friends to spend a quiet day with
this confused me and I started to wonder
if I was just anti-social or broken in
some way I left people I've always loved
people their stories ideas their flaws
as well as their dreams
and yet close and intimate friendships
were something I felt was often Out Of
Reach
I thought my problem was that I spent
too much time alone and so once I got
into my late teens I reinvented myself
pushing away the side of me that just
wanted a cozy night in in exchange for
clubbing and nights out
foreign
[Music]
T able to sustain a big social life
without starting to deeply miss my books
and aloneness I found it difficult to
find people that were comfortable enough
to share their vulnerability leading to
those heart-to-heart conversations I
craved so deeply
I often felt I made people uncomfortable
by sharing my feelings and yet I knew
there must be a lot of people out there
like me
the answer unsurprisingly was simply to
be patient and remember that finding
your Kindred Spirits may take a lifetime
I eventually discovered Souls I hold
very dear and contribute greatly to my
sons of belonging and I in return
but in the process of not having friends
for most of my childhood and a good
portion of my adult life I started to
realize a very interesting thing
and that was that I didn't mind as much
as I thought I would I still needed
connection and got involved in book
clubs and other activities but when it
came to close Kindred Spirits it took
years and years to find them
I had started my hero's journey apart
from family alone and I had embraced it
channeling energy into my art and dreams
for the future and it was only until I
began comparing myself to societal norms
and my peers that I started to fret that
something was wrong perhaps much of our
dissatisfaction can be ameliorated by
simply remembering our path as our own
and that we will find our way
laughs
foreign
[Music]
the thermometer on my car said it was
negative one early this morning and I
don't know how accurate that was but it
does feel extremely cold I have to admit
I have no plans to leave the house today
I had a wonderful birthday week and I
appreciate all the well wishes I got we
went out to dinner and I got a couple
little gifts and it was really lovely as
many of you know I spent my entire life
moving from place to place growing up in
a military family and this is the first
time living here in this little town and
this tiny Rural Valley that I have felt
that I can really set down my roots and
build a community and start to meet
people and connect with people on a more
permanent basis meeting new people and
cultivating friendships has never been
something very easy for me it has gotten
drastically easier as I've gotten older
but especially in my very young adult
years as I'm still a young adult
I really struggled with connection and
finding Maya tribe in a way and I have
to admit as someone who is quite
introverted friendships are very
important to me but also time alone and
a lot of time kind of alone at home is
something I value as well or at least
alone with family or in an environment
that's you know really comfortable for
me for so long I really internalized
those values you know of what made
someone well adjusted or healthy and
that being someone who has a large group
of friends and is always doing social
things and I think that's so wonderful
and I love that there's so many you know
extremely social lovely people in this
world who value that because the world
would be very dull if we were all the
same but I think it is worth reminding
our little people and reminding
ourselves that having only a handful of
quality friends or if those friends are
simply family or if those friends are
just a couple select people that we
might not even have in our general area
I know for some people friendships with
animals are just as meaningful and I
think it's so wonderful to you know
celebrate that so that there are all
sorts of friendships and bonds and
relationships that we might be
comfortable with depending on our
personality I am so happy now to be in a
place where I do have several people I
call friends including people at work in
my personal life as well as having
created some really close relationships
within my own family I also deeply
appreciate just spending time with my
puppy and my cat and spending time in
nature feels very fulfilling as well I
know especially as someone who really
enjoys children's movies and cartoons
still as an adult I know that friendship
is often put on an extremely high
platform as if it is the goal that
everyone needs to meet in order to find
belonging and fulfillment and acceptance
and I think in a way that for sure is
true you know our connections with other
humans are very important to our sense
of well-being when I first moved to this
Valley I didn't know anyone and it took
me a long time to make friends but in
the meantime I worked at a preschool I
connected with children I connected with
those families and even though I wasn't
really spending time with anyone outside
of work it was extremely fulfilling and
I felt like I deeply belonged to my own
Community I also consider my husband one
of my best friends and it is just so
wonderful to just spend time with him so
yes all through my early school years
through high school and even through a
good portion of University
I did not feel at all like I had friends
and I had people that I was close with
so I really have embraced that idea of
quality over quantity and I've also
though
Embrace that idea that if there are
times in your life where you feel
disconnected you feel like you haven't
yet met your people
to see that as a beautiful time that can
have a lot of meaning and a lot of
benefit and you might even realize that
you enjoy spending time with yourself
and that doesn't mean that anything is
wrong with you that doesn't mean that
you are lacking in some way
for me some books that have really
deeply helped me in my journey
especially when I was younger
understanding myself was quiet and the
highly sensitive person
I found both of those to be extremely
helpful and I still recommend them to
this day to older children who are
trying to understand themselves and why
they need so much quality time alone or
if they struggle with anxiety or
emotional regulation you know it's very
normal there's a lot of people that feel
the way you feel you are never alone
also I wanted to say a big thank you for
all the encouraging words in my last
video as you may be able to tell some of
my videos have been a little shorter
lately and that has been my attempt to
take a little more time to figure out
what I want to do with this channel in
the future and what I'm going to be
doing next year and it is definitely a
journey I have some projects I want to
work on that I would like to share with
all of you some ideas for children's
books and other projects so so we shall
see I really don't know I am
lost in a good way thinking about that
quote not all who wander are lost right
so yes I will keep you updated as things
go and I will be uploading a q a very
soon because I wanted to finally answer
some questions that have been haunting
this channel for a long time so look
forward to that in a couple days or so
and I will see you very soon
take care
goodbye
foreign